Vincent is a animation, fantasy film directed by Tim Burton.
Young Vincent Malloy dreams of being just like Vincent Price and loses
himself in macabre daydreams that annoy his mother.
Narrator (voice), played by Vincent Price.
Vincent is a 1982 American gothic stop-motion animated short film written,
designed and directed by Tim Burton, and produced by Rick Heinrichs.
The film is narrated by actor Vincent Price, a
lifelong idol of and inspiration for Burton.
From this relationship, Price would go on to appear
in Burton's Edward Scissorhands.
Vincent Price later said that Vincent was "the most
gratifying thing that ever happened.
It was immortality — better than a star on Hollywood Boulevard."
There is currently
no individual release of the film except for a few bootleg releases.
It can be found on the 2008 Special Edition and Collector's Edition DVDs of The Nightmare
Before Christmas as a bonus feature and on the Cinema16 DVD American Short Films.
The film explores themes of narration, mama's boy,
stop motion, spoof, black and white.